SUMMARY

Data driven and performance aware software engineer who strives to impact and deliver value. Experienced in data science, backend software development, and electronic trading. Ardent automator of software testing and champion of business process simplification/automation.

SKILLS

- Data-oriented and object-oriented design with C++ and Java, programming with C and Python
- Data modelling, engineering and analysis with SQL, PL/SQL (Oracle, MS SQL Server, Db2), MongoDB
- Small team leadership, collaboration with Git, GitHub, Jira, Confluence
- Full stack web development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Bootstrap, Node.js
- Delivery and development methodologies including CI/CD, TDD, Agile

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data and Reporting Analyst – RBC Royal Bank, Toronto ON

Apr 2023 - Current

 Operationalizing case management aspect of privacy access monitoring initiative by applying automation and data modelling skills, enabling the expansion of initiative to all regions in Canada

Software Developer Intern – RBC Capital Markets, Toronto ON

Jan 2023 – Apr 2023

- Ensuring regulatory testing requirements are met by applying **electronic trading** and **Java** skills to deliver enhancements to existing simulation/testing software (Ragnarok), resulting in financial penalty avoidance
- Working closely with automation engineer to improve regression testing for new releases by applying **electronic trading** and **C++** skills to upgrade internal testing toolkit, resulting in richer and more automatic testing process

Data and Reporting Analyst – RBC Royal Bank, Toronto ON

May 2022 – Jan 2023

 Automated highly manual and time-consuming business process by applying data modelling and data analysis skills to implement a 3rd party dataware solution, resulting in 100+ hours of labour being saved each year going forward

PROJECTS

swan – <u>GitHub Repo</u> | *Tech Stack: C++, Dear ImGui*

• Applying **C++** and **performance-aware programming** skills to develop a faster, more pleasant replacement for Windows File Explorer and eventually Command Prompt in weekend sprint fashion

Langton's Ant Explorer – GitHub Repo | Tech Stack: C++

• Discovering complex Langton's Ant patterns by applying **C++** and **performance-aware programming** skills to develop an efficient simulation toolchain

Ctructure - GitHub Repo | Tech Stack: TypeScript

• Led team of 2 in agile development of code formatter for the C programming language, resulting in a productivity tool which is easier to configure and use than popular alternatives such as clang-format

EDUCATION

Computer Programming Diploma, High Honours – Seneca College, Toronto ON

Sep 2019 – Dec 2022